var gQuizData = [

  {
    category: "język angielski",
    questionFormat: {prefix: "Po angielsku ", postfix: " to?"},
    data: [
      {
        name: "liczby",
        data: [
          {question: "1", answer: "one"},
          {question: "2", answer: "two"},
          {question: "3", answer: "three"},
          {question: "4", answer: "four"},
          {question: "5", answer: "five"},
          {question: "6", answer: "six"},
          {question: "7", answer: "seven"},
          {question: "8", answer: "eight"},
          {question: "9", answer: "nine"},
          {question: "10", answer: "ten"}
        ]
      },
      {
        name: "kolory",
        data: [
          {question: "czerwony", answer: "red"},
          {question: "niebieski", answer: "blue"},
          {question: "brązowy", answer: "brown"},
          {question: "fioletowy", answer: "purple"},      
          {question: "zielony", answer: "green"},
          {question: "żółty", answer: "yellow"},
          {question: "biały", answer: "white"},
          {question: "czarny", answer: "black"},
          {question: "brązowy", answer: "brown"},
          {question: "różowy", answer: "pink"}
        ]
      },
      {
        name: "małe zwierzęta",
        data: [
          {question: "gąsienica", answer: "caterpillar"},
          {question: "biedronka", answer: "ladybird"},
          {question: "mrówka", answer: "ant"},
          {question: "ślimak", answer: "snail"},
          {question: "pszczoła", answer: "bee"},
          {question: "motyl", answer: "butterfly"}
        ]
      },
      {
        name: "duże zwierzęta",
        data: [
          {question: "lew", answer: "lion"},
          {question: "słoń", answer: "elephant"},
          {question: "zebra", answer: "zebra"},
          {question: "żyrafa", answer: "giraffe"},
          {question: "papuga", answer: "parrot"},
          {question: "mysz", answer: "mouse"}
        ]
      },
      {
        name: "zabawki",
        data: [
          {question: "hulajnoga", answer: "scooter"},
          {question: "miś", answer: "bear"},      
          {question: "piłka", answer: "ball"},
          {question: "rower", answer: "bike"},
          {question: "lalka", answer: "doll"},
          {question: "robot", answer: "robot"},
          {question: "auto", answer: "car"}
        ]
      },
      {
        name: "części ciała",
        data: [
          {question: "oczy", answer: "eyes"},
          {question: "uszy", answer: "ears"},
          {question: "nos", answer: "nose"},      
          {question: "usta", answer: "mouth"},
          {question: "palce", answer: "fingers"},
          {question: "palce u stóp", answer: "toes"}
        ]
      },
      {
        name: "jedzonko",
        data: [
          {question: "jajka", answer: "eggs"},
          {question: "jajko", answer: "egg"},
          {question: "kurczak", answer: "chicken"},
          {question: "ser", answer: "cheese"},
          {question: "szynka", answer: "ham"},
          {question: "jabłko", answer: "apple"},
          {question: "jabłka", answer: "apples"},
          {question: "gruszka", answer: "pear"},
          {question: "gruszki", answer: "pears"},      
          {question: "pomarańcza", answer: "orange"},
          {question: "pomarańcze", answer: "oranges"},      
          {question: "banan", answer: "banana"},
          {question: "banany", answer: "bananas"},
          {question: "pomidory", answer: "tomatoes"},
          {question: "sałata", answer: "lettuce"}
        ]
      },
      {
        name: "czynności",
        data: [
          {question: "słuchać", answer: "listen"},
          {question: "grać", answer: "play"},
          {question: "pisać", answer: "write"},
          {question: "czytać", answer: "read"},      
          {question: "latać", answer: "fly"},
          {question: "liczyć", answer: "count"},
          {question: "śpiewać", answer: "sing"},
          {question: "biegać", answer: "run"},
          {question: "skakać", answer: "jump"},
          {question: "dotknąć", answer: "touch"},
          {question: "pływać", answer: "swim"}
          
        ]
      },
      {
        name: "dom/rodzina",
        data: [
          {question: "mama", answer: "mummy"},
          {question: "tata", answer: "daddy"},
          {question: "dziecko", answer: "baby"},
          {question: "miś", answer: "bear"},
          {question: "duży", answer: "big"},
          {question: "mały", answer: "small"},
          {question: "malutki", answer: "tiny"},
          {question: "siostra", answer: "sister"},
          {question: "brat", answer: "brother"},
          {question: "krzesło", answer: "chair"},
          {question: "miska", answer: "bowl"},
          {question: "łóżko", answer: "bed"}
        ]
      }
    ]
  }, 
  
  {
    category: "ortografia",
    questionFormat: {prefix: "Napisz poprawnie ", postfix: ""},
    data: [
      {
        name: "   ó   /   u  cz.1 ",
        data: [
          {question: "m_zg", answer: "mózg"},
          {question: "kt_ry", answer: "który"},      
          {question: "zachm_rzyło", answer: "zachmurzyło"},
          {question: "g_ra", answer: "góra"},      
          {question: "żagl_wka", answer: "żaglówka"},
          {question: "s_l", answer: "sól"},
          {question: "wrz_cić", answer: "wrzucić"},
          {question: "rz_t", answer: "rzut"},
          {question: "d_ł", answer: "dół"},
          {question: "wr_bel", answer: "wróbel"},
          {question: "kr_lik", answer: "królik"},
          {question: "samoch_d", answer: "samochód"},
          {question: "pi_rnik", answer: "piórnik"},
          {question: "g_rnym", answer: "górnym"},
          {question: "d_ł", answer: "dół"}
        ]
      },


{
        name: "   ó   /   u  cz.2 ",
        data: [
          {question: "odejm_jemy", answer: "odejmujemy"},
          {question: "k_ć obręcz", answer: "kuć obręcz"},      
          {question: "k_łko", answer: "kółko"},
          {question: "m_wimy", answer: "mówimy"},      
          {question: "r_żnice", answer: "różnice"},
          {question: "pom_gł", answer: "pomógł"},
          {question: "przyni_sł", answer: "przyniósł"},
          {question: "szan_j", answer: "szanuj"},
          {question: "p_ł", answer: "pół"},
           {question: "r_ch", answer: "ruch"},
          {question: "sł_ch", answer: "słuch"},
          {question: "kr_l", answer: "król"},
          {question: "b_ty", answer: "buty"},
          {question: "mi_d", answer: "miód"},
          {question: "g_ral", answer: "góral"},
          {question: "g_rnym", answer: "górnym"},
          {question: "d_ł", answer: "dół"}
        ]
      },


    {
        name: "   ż   /   rz   cz.1 ",
        data: [  
          {question: "któ_y", answer: "którzy"},
          {question: "zachmu_yło", answer: "zachmurzyło"},          
          {question: "stra_", answer: "straż"},
          {question: "gó_ysty", answer: "górzysty"},      
          {question: "_aglówka", answer: "żaglówka"},
          {question: "księ_niczka", answer: "księżniczka"},
          {question: "w_ucić", answer: "wrzucić"},
          {question: "_ut", answer: "rzut"},
          {question: "żołnie_", answer: "żołnierz"},
          {question: "ró_nice", answer: "różnice"},
          {question: "_ołnierz", answer: "żołnierz"}
        ]
      },
{
        name: "   ż   /   rz   cz.2 ",
        data: [  
          {question: "mo_e głębokie", answer: "morze głębokie"},
          {question: "wie_a", answer: "wieża"},          
          {question: "le_y", answer: "leży"},
          {question: "_ycie", answer: "życie"},      
          {question: "zwie_ęta", answer: "zwierzęta"},
          {question: "_e", answer: "że"},
          {question: "t_eba", answer: "trzeba"},
          {question: "zło_yć", answer: "złożyć"},
          {question: "l_ejszy", answer: "lżejszy"},
          {question: "ró_nice", answer: "różnice"},
          {question: "l_ejszy", answer: "lżejszy"},
          {question: "ni_szy", answer: "niższy"},
          {question: "wy_szy", answer: "wyższy"}
        ]
      },

{
        name: "   h   /   ch   ",
        data: [  
          {question: "który_", answer: "których"},
          {question: "za_murzyło", answer: "zachmurzyło"},   
          {question: "samo_ód", answer: "samochód"},
          {question: "_odnik", answer: "chodnik"},
          {question: "ko_ać", answer: "kochać"},
          {question: "zapa_", answer: "zapach"},
          {question: "ru_", answer: "ruch"},
          {question: "wę_", answer: "węch"},
          {question: "słu_", answer: "słuch"},
          {question: "_oinka", answer: "choinka"},
          {question: "górny_", answer: "górnych"},   
          {question: "dolny_", answer: "dolnych"}
        ]
      },        
{
        name: "inne",
        data: [
          {question: "móz_", answer: "mózg"},
          {question: "myśl_c", answer: "myśląc"},
          {question: "zwierz_ta", answer: "zwierzęta"},
          {question: "p_enica", answer: "pszenica"},
          {question: "zd_ęcie", answer: "zdjęcie"},
          {question: "zdj_cie", answer: "zdjęcie"}      
        
        ]
      }        
    ]
  }
];